****翻译:法兰克彼得生****
Why not call it the Pecu?
Or the Nipia one?
为什么不叫它其它什么名？
I'm just saying how do we know
it's an ice age?
我是说为什么我们知道现在是冰河世纪。
Because of all the ices!
就因为这些冰川！
Well , things just
got a little peculiar.
好的，事情变的有点奇怪了。
Help! Help!
救命！救命！
Come on, kids, let's go.
The berg is moving.
别玩了，孩子们。我们走。
灾难就要来了。
But, dad. . .
但是，爸爸....
No "but".
You can play later.
没什么“但是”。
你以后可以玩。
Okay.
Come on, guys.
好的，来吧，兄弟们。
Sally, where's Eddie?
赛利，艾迪在哪？
He said something about being on a
verge of a revolutionary breakthrough.
他说什么：现在是进化突破的关键阶段。
Really?
真的吗？
I'm flying!
我飞了！
Some breakthrough.
这就是一些突破。
Look out!
A mammoth is on its way.
小心呀。
猛玛象来了。
Hey, do the world a favour!
嗨，帮个忙！
Move your issue off the road!
不要挡路。
If my trunk was that small ,
I wouldn't draw attention to myself, pal .
如果我个头和你一样，我也不会引人注目，朋友。
Give me a break.
让我休息下。
We've been wandering with our babies.
我们一直带着孩子们走了半天。
Go ahead. Follow the crowd.
快去吧。跟着大伙。
Be quiet when you're gone.
走的时候，声音小点。
Come on.
走吧。
I'm up, I'm up!
上，上！
Rising sign, everybody.
大家好。
Zeke? Mashu?
齐克？马修？
Birdie? Uncle Fungis?
波尔弟？芬基斯叔叔？
Where is everybody?
大家在哪？
Come on, guys.
We gonna miss the mi . . .
来呀。兄弟们，你们将会错过....
My patient.
我的病人。
They left without me.
他们扔下我就走了。
They do this every year!
每年他们都这样！
Why? Doesn't anyone love me?
为什么？为什么没有喜欢我？
Isn't there anyone who cares
about Sid the Sloth?
为什么没有人关心我这树懒--希德。
All right, I'll just go by myself.
没关系，我自己走。
Oh. Stinks!
噢，臭死了！
Hey, wait, buddy!
Tell me next time!
嗨，等一等，兄弟！
下次你得告诉我。
I can't believe it.
Fresh and green.
真不能相信。
它还是绿色新鲜的。
Frank, you're cutest ever.
弗兰克，你真可爱。
Go ahead, pick it.
来呀，捡起它。
A dandelion.
I thought the frost wipe them all out.
蒲公英。
我还以为霜冻把他们都消灭了呢。
All but one.
就剩这一朵了。
Make me so. . .
让我真....
This is definitely not been my day.
You know what I'm saying, buddy?
今天可真倒霉。
你知道我在说什么吧。
What a mess.
真混乱。
Hey, you rhino, you have really
nice race, do you know that?
嗨，犀牛，你跑起来真好看，
你自己知道不？
It's just a fact.
我说的是事实。
You know what I'm talking about.
你知道我在说什么吧。
A dandelion.
蒲公英。
Must be the last one of season.
肯定是这季里的最后一朵。
Carlo.
Easy, Frankie.
卡罗，放松，弗兰克。
He ruined our salad.
他毁了我们的“沙拉”。
Oh, my mistake.
It's my mistake. Let me. . .
噢，是我的错。是我的错。
让我....
No, seriously, let me take care of this.
不，我是认真的，让我们小心这玩意儿。
Oh. What is this?
噢，这是什么？
My goodness, that's my favourite.
上帝呀，我最喜欢吃的。
Hmm , delicious.
美味。
That's a. . .good eating.
这可好吃的东西。
Don't let me have it all .
Yes, you have some.
我不能独吞。
你们也尝尝。
Tasty, isn't it?
不错吧？
Gonna have to pick tooth.
我去剔牙了。
Now?
现在？
Now.
Please save me.
请救救我。
I wanna hit him full speed.
我真想打死他。
That's okay, Frank.
We'll have some fun with him .
好的，弗兰克。
让我们和他玩玩。
Don't let them kill me, please.
I wanna live!
请不要让他们杀我。
我想活。
Get off me!
滚开。
Come on, you're making a scene.
来呀，你要出洋相了。
We just take off free and go.
Do your mind?
我们要把他带走，你不介意吧。
Buddy, if not them today,
it's just someone else tomorrow.
兄弟，如果今天不是他们，明日也自有那人。
I rather not be today. Okay?
我宁愿今天没有，好吗？
Gotta break your neck so you
don't feel the pain. How's that?
扭断你的脖子，你就不知道痛了，
怎么样？
Wait a minute.
I thought rhinos are vegetarians.
等一下。在我印象里，犀牛是素食者。
An active point.
Shut up!
说的好！
闭嘴。
Who says we gonna eat him
after we kill him?
谁说杀了他之后，我们要吃他。
Come on, move it.
来吧，开始吧。
You know, I don't like
animals to kill for pleasure.
你知道不，我不喜欢动物为了消遣杀人。
Sid, for matters that cares.
希德，就是我们要杀的。
I'm the matter that cares.
我就是他们要杀的。
Okay, look. If either of you make it
好的，听着。如果你们中有谁
across that sink hole in front of you,
you get this one.
能穿过这个圈进来，他就是你们的了。
That's right, you losers.
You take a step and you're dead.
好的，你们这些失败者。
敢往前你们就死定了。
You're bluffing, huh?
Yeah, that was a bluff.
你在骗人？
是的，我就在骗人。
Go!
上！
A dandelion?
蒲公英？
We're steady!
我们赢了！
What?
什么？
You have beautiful eyes.
你的眼睛真漂亮。
Get off my face.
从我脸上下来。
You and me, we make a great team .
你和我在一起，肯定不错。
What do you say
we just head South together?
你说我们向南走怎么样？
Yeah, jump on my back
and relax your whole way.
好的，跳到我背上来，让你一路轻松。
Really?
No.
真的？
骗你的。
Wait, aren't you going to South?
等一下。你不是向南走吗。
The changing season,
emigrational things?
现在可是季节交替，大伙搬家的时候。
Is it ringing a bell?
I guess not, pal .
让你想起了什么？
我想没有。
Okay, thanks for the help.
I can take it from here.
好的，谢谢你的帮助。
从这，我可以自己走。
Hey, you over grown weasel .
Wait till we get down there.
嗨，你这个胆小鬼。
敢在那儿等我们下来吗。
The whole South thing is way out.
The heat, the crowd.
南方也没什么好的。天又热，人又多。
This great. You and me, two guys
knocking about in the wild.
这样也好，你和我，俩个人一起在野外闲逛。
No, you just want a bodyguard
so you don't become somebody's side dish.
不，你只需要一个保镖，免得你成了别人的盘中餐。
You're very strut mammoth.
你可真是个“自信”的猛玛象。
Can you lead the way, Mr. Big Guy?
你能带路吗，大块头先生？
Manfred.
曼菲德。
How about Mandy the moody
mammoth or nanny the. . .
曼迪（曼菲德的爱称）这只喜怒无常的猛玛象
怎么样....？
Stop following me.
不要跟着我。
Okay, so you got it.
You won't even know I'm here.
好的。你明白了。我不说话，你根本不知道我在这儿。
I'll just zip the lip when I say. . .
我会闭上嘴的，只有当我说....
Look at the cute little baby, Diego.
看看那可爱的婴儿，迭哥。
Isn't it nice if he joining us for breakfast?
把他当早餐肯定不错。
It wouldn't be breakfast without him .
没了他早餐都没味了。
His daddy wiped our hair for pack.
And rag our skin to keep warm .
他爸爸用我们的毛来包裹，
穿我们的皮来保暖。
And ruin our lives. Don't you think?
毁了我们的生活,你觉的呢?
Let show that human what happen
when he messed with Sabers.
让他们看看惹了我们剑齿虎会有什么下场?
Alert the troops.
We attack at dawn.
让部队警戒。
我们天亮时进攻。
And Diego, bring me that baby. Alive.
迭哥，你去把那婴儿带来，要活的。
If I'm gonna enjoy my revenge,
I want it to be fresh.
如果我要享受复仇的快感，那孩子死了可不行。
I'm wiped out.
我累死了。
That's your shelter?
那就是你的庇护所？
You're a big guy. You got a lot of
woods. I'm a little guy.
你是个大块头。你能拿这么多木头。
我个头小，我可不行。
You only got a stick.
你只拿了一根木头。
Yeah, but with my little stick,
and my highly evolved brain. . .
是的，用这根小小的木头，再加上
我那高度进化的脑袋.....
I'll start the fire.
我就能生起火起。
Fascinating.
真奇妙。
We'll see if breeze try to blow us
tonight. Now won't we?
今天晚上我们就知道有没有微风吹出来了。
是吧？
Hey, I think I saw its flare.
嗨，我想我看到火花了。
Any chance I can squeeze
in there with you?
我能挤进来吗？
Isn't there someone else you can annoy?
你就不会去烦别人？
Friends? Family?
Poison reptiles?
朋友？家人？
毒虫？
My family is bad.
They just kind of migrate without me.
我的家人可不好。
他们每次搬家都不带上我。
You should see what they did last year.
你得看看他们去年做了什么。
They woke up early and
they tied my hands and feet together.
他们早就醒了，然后把我的手脚绑起来。
They buried the cave door,
and covered their tracks.
他们把洞门埋了，又擦了他们足迹。
They made it anyway.
他们就是这样。
So what about you? You got family?
你呢？你有家人吗？
Okay, you're tired, I see.
We'll talk tomorrow morning.
好的，看的出，你累了。
我们明天谈。
Manfred? Manfred.
曼菲德？曼菲德。
Could you move over?
挪过去点儿？
Come on, nobody fall asleep that fast.
不会吧，没人能这么快就睡着了。
Mandy!
曼迪？
That's Diego, fall back!
那是迭哥，撤退！
Where's the baby?
那婴儿在哪？
I lost it over the falls.
You lost it?
我在瀑布那儿把他丢了。
你把他丢了。
I want that baby, Diego.
I'll get it.
我要他孩子，迭哥。
我会找回来的。
You better. Unless you want to serve
yourself as the replacement.
最好如此。不然你就要做他的替代品。
We'll go up to half peak. Meet us there.
我们会去半山腰，在那儿见。
It'd better be alive.
最好是活的。
Can we trust you with that, Diego?
我们能相信你吗，迭哥？
Let's go!
我们走！
And you pick this year off my shoulders.
你今年就靠我吧。
If you gonna have a mating partner,
如果你想找个伴侣，
at least pick a female
with the same color palette, right?
起码也得找个同样肤色的，是吧？
And I thought, wow, he's gonna go
primal , you know what I'm saying?
我想，他要返朴归真了，你知道我在说什么吧？
If you find a mate in life,
you should be loyal .
如果你找到终生伴侣，你就得对她忠贞。
In your case, it's grateful .
Get away from me.
你能这么说，真是让人感动。
离我远点儿。
Well , I think mate in life is stupid.
I mean everybody just sit around. . .
是的，我想“终生伴侣”这个观念简直是可笑。
我是说每人都只是坐在那.....
Mandy?
曼迪？
Look at that.
He's okay.
看看他。
他没事。
She's gone.
她漂走了。
Hey, Mandy,
are you forgetting something?
嗨，曼迪。你没忘什么东西吧？
No.
But you just saved him .
没有。
但是你救了他。
Yeah, but I'm still trying
to get rid of the last thing I saved.
是的，我还想摆脱我上一次救的东西呢。
You can't leave him here.
你不能留下他。
Look, there's smoke.
看，那儿有烟。
That's his heir right up the hill .
We should return him .
他的族人就在那山上。
我们得去还了他。
Let's get something straight.
There's no "we".
有些事得说清楚。
这里没什么“我们”。
There never was a "we".
也永远不会有“我们”。
In fact, without me,
there wouldn't even be a "you"!
事实上，没有我。
你连个“你”也算不上。
Just up the hill .
就在山上。
Listen very carefully.
I'm not g-o-i-n-g.
听清楚。
我-不-去。
Fine. Be a jerk.
好的，自己待着吧。
I'll take care of him .
我会照顾他。
Go. Yeah, that's good.
好，是，真不错。
You take care of him?
You can't even take care of yourself.
你能照顾他？
你连自己照顾不了。
This I gotta see.
这是我的结论。
I'll return him .
We don't need that Mandy.
我会把你送回去。
我们不用曼迪。
You know we do.
你知道我们行的。
You're embarrassing the nature,
do you know that?
你让自然尴尬，你知道自己在做什么吧？
I'm fine. I'm fine!
我很好。我很好！
I'm gonna die.
我要死了。
That thing is mine.
那东西是我的！
No, actually that thing belongs to us.
不，事实上，他是我们的。
Us?
You two are barely a couple.
我们？
你们俩是一对。
There is no "us".
I see.
这里可没有“我们”。
You can have one of your own
so you won't adopt.
你们自己生一个吧。不用收养。
Look, I'm sorry to interrupt this.
不好意思，打扰一下。
But we gotta go.
我们必须走了。
The baby, please.
那个婴儿。
I'm returning to his heir.
我正要把他送到他族人那儿。
Oh, yeah. Nice try, bucktooth.
好的，真棒，大獠牙。
You're calling me a lair?
I didn't say that.
你说我是个骗子？
我可没说。
You were thinking it.
你是这么想的。
I don't like this cat.
He reads mind.
我可不喜欢这只猫科动物。
他能知道别人怎么想的。
Name is Diego, friend.
朋友，我叫迭哥。
Manfred. And I'm not your friend.
曼菲德。你不是我的朋友。
Fine, Manfred.
好的，曼菲德。
If you're looking for its heir,
you're wasting your time.
如果你们是在找他的族人，
那你们是在白费时间。
He left this morning.
他们今天早上就离开了。
Thanks for the advice. I beat this.
谢谢你的建议，我知道了。
All right, I'll help you bring it to its heir.
好的，我会找你找到他的族人的。
But promise me
you'd leave me alone after that.
但你得保证，完事后，你得离开我。
Okay, deal .
好的，没问题。
What's your problem?
You're my problem .
你有什么问题？
你就是我的问题。
But I think you're stressed.
That's why you eat so much.
但我觉得你很紧张。
这就是为什么总吃那么多。
It's hard to get fat on a diet.
你要是节食就胖不起来了。
I'm not fat. It's all this fur.
It makes me look puffy.
我不是胖，是我的毛，让我看起来膨膨的。
All right, yeah. Fat hair.
But when you're ready to talk, I'm here.
好的，长毛。
什么时候你想聊天，我随时奉陪。
Just drop it on the land.
把他放在地上就行了。
Shouldn't we make sure they found
him? Good idea.
我们不确定一下他的族人找到他了。
好，就这么办。
No, no, no!
Wait.
不，不，不！
等一下。
Don't spear me!
不要刺我！
This is a problem .
这儿有个问题。
Now what?
什么？
That's perfect.
真不错。
I told you they were gone.
我给你们说了，他们已经走了。
Look who it is.
看看那是谁？
Don't you have some flaw
defenseless animals to disembogue?
你难道没什么小动物吃了吗？
They couldn't be far.
They went this way?
他们走不远。
他们走的是这条路。
Or this way?
或者是这条路。
You don't know much
about tracking, do you?
你不太了解追踪吧？
I must lost. I see trees,
either leaves, that's my tracking.
我肯定会迷路的。要么是那些树木，要么是那些树叶。
我就凭着它们来追踪的。
You didn't miss them by much.
你不会离他们很远的。
It's still green.
还是温的。
They head north 2 hours ago.
他们两小时前向北走了。
Is it? They head north 2 hours ago.
是吗？他们两小时前向北走了。
You don't need this aggravation.
你不需要这个小讨厌。
Give me the baby.
把那孩子给我。
I can track human down
faster than you can.
我会追踪人类，比你们要快的多。
And you're just a good citizen
helping out, right?
你真是个见义勇为的好市民？
I just know where the human will go.
我只是知道人们会往哪儿走。
Find the pass.
找出他们的足迹。
Everybody knows they have
a settlement on the other side.
大家都知道他们在那边有个居住地。
Unless you know how to track,
除非你知道怎样追踪，
you never gonna reach them
before their pass closed up with snow.
不然，在雪掩埋了他们足迹之前，你们
是永远找不到他们的。
Which should be like, tomorrow.
那是什么时候。
明天。
So you can give that baby to me
or go get lost in the blizzard.
要么你把那孩子给我，
要么在雪地里迷路。
It's your choice.
你自己选吧。
Here's your little bundle of joy.
We'll return it to the human.
这是你的小可爱。
让我们把他还回去。
Big bad Tiddy Widdy get cliff.
Poor Tiddy Widdy. . .
大坏老虎仔碰壁了。
可怜的老虎仔....
Sid, Tiddy Widdy is gonna lead the way.
希德，老虎仔为我们带路。
Mandy, can I talk to you for a second?
曼迪，能和谈一分钟吗？
No.
不行。
The sooner we find the human,
the sooner I get rid of Mr. Stinky-drew-face.
越快找到那些人类，我越能越快摆脱臭脸先生。
And the baby too.
还有这婴儿。
You always have that jumbo
around to protect you.
那大家伙总在附近保护你。
And when that day comes,
I suggest you watch your back.
从现在起，你得小心你的背后。
Cause I'll be tuning on it.
因为我会扑上来。
Human tracker,
up front so I can see you.
人类追踪者，到前面来，让我能看见你。
Help me.
救命。
You gotta make him stop.
I can't tolerate anymore!
你得让他别哭了。
我受不了了。
I think this thing didn't complain this much.
我觉得没什么好报怨的。
Stop shouting at me.
You're holding it wrong.
不要对我喊了。
你的抱法不对。
Watch its head!
Just put it down.
小心他的头。
把他放下来。
Its nose is dry.
他的鼻子是干的。
That means something is wrong with it.
这就是说他出了点儿问题。
Maybe we should lick it.
Just in case.
我们可能要舔舔他。以防万一。
I'll do it.
我来做吧。
You know, the baby stinks.
你知道的，那孩子臭死了。
So if it poops, where does it go?
如果他拉屎了，我们怎么办？
Humans are disgusting.
人类真恶心。
Okay, you.
好的，你。
Check for poop.
来检查下他有没有拉屎。
Why am I the poop checker?
为什么是我？
Because returning it is your idea.
Because you're small and insignificant
就因为还这个孩子是你的主意。
就因为你个头小，无关紧要。
And because I'll pound you if you don't.
还因为你如果说“不”，我就要揍你。
What else?
Now, Sid!
还有什么？
现在，希德。
I mean, my goodness.
我是说，上帝呀。
All right, look out. Coming through.
好的，小心。拉出来了。
Watch out!
Stop waving it around!
小心！
不要摆来摆去。
Oh, I'm gonna slip!
噢，我要滑倒了！
It's clean! Got you!
干净了。我做完了。
Would you cut it out!
你把它弄断了！
Hey, do that again.
He likes it.
再来一次。
他喜欢这样。
That makes me feel better too.
也让我好受多了。
Turn him towards me.
让他看着我。
Where is the baby?
There it is!
孩子在哪？
就在这里。
Where is the baby?
孩子在哪？
There it is!
就在这里。
Stop it! You're scaring it!
停下，你吓着他了。
I bet he's hungry.
我打赌他是饿了。
How about some milk?
来点牛奶怎么样？
I'd love some.
Not you, the baby.
我喜欢。
不是给你的，是给那孩子的。
I ain't exactly doing it right now, pal .
伙计，我现在可没做。
You alone are the food
jamming mouth, aren't you?
你自己不就能塞进嘴的食物吗？
Enough!
够了！
Food!
吃的！
Prepare for ice age!
为冰河世纪做准备！
Protect the Dodo valley!
保卫渡渡鸟山谷！
Survivals separate the Dodo off the peak!
为了生存渡渡鸟远离山顶！
Protect the Dodo valley!
保卫渡渡鸟山谷！
Prepare for ice age!
为冰河世纪做准备！
Ice age?
冰河世纪？
I've heard of these cracks, buddy.
我已经听过那些碎裂声了，哥们。
Intruders!
入侵者！
Don't fall in. if you do, you'll physically. . .
不要掉进去，如果掉进去了，你就会.....
Intruders!
入侵者！
Burned and died.
被烧死。
Hey, can we have our melon back?
嗨，我们能拿回我们的瓜吗？
Junior is hungry and. . .
小孩饿了，而且...
No way! This is our private
stuff for ice age.
不行。这是为冰河世纪准备的私人物品。
Some of us has been looking
around for billions billions years.
我们找了不知多少年才找到的。
So you got three melons?
才找到三个？
If you weren't smart,
and I'll cut it into half and throw on you.
如果你不放聪明点儿，
我就切了它扔到你头上。
Wait for me.
等我。
No!
不！
Retrieve the melon!
夺回那些瓜！
Attack!
进攻！
The melon!
那瓜！
There goes our last female.
我们最后的女性没了。
The last melon!
还有一个瓜！
That's it.
就是这样。
Now we gonna find more food.
现在我们得多找点吃的。
We got dinner on the shore.
我们去岸边吃吧。
Now the meal will be feeding a hungry sloth.
现在一只树懒要吃东西了。
With who?
A vole?
和谁?
一只野鼠?
Come on, you wanna fist me?
来呀,你不是想打我吗?
Bedtime.
该睡觉了.
The triumph has returned.
胜利者回来了.
Shuffle.
饱死了.
How about a good night kiss for you?
来个"晚安吻"怎么样?
Shh. It's asleep.
嘘,他睡着了.
I was talking to you.
我在和你说话。
Fine, I'll tuck myself in.
好的，我自己吃。
Good night.
晚安。
Would you stop that!
你能停下吗！
All right. All right.
好的，好的。
Trying to relax.
放松。
All right.
好的。
What the. . .
你想....
Go ahead. Slice me.
继续呀，把我撕碎。
It'll be the last thing you'd ever do.
那将是你这辈子最后干的事。
I'm working here, you wasted fur.
废物，你没看见我在这儿工作吗？
For who, Diego?
为了谁，迭哥？
Tracking down human
is too difficult for you?
追踪人类对你来说太难了？
What are you two doing here?
你们俩来这干什么？
Soto's getting tired of waiting.
索多已经等的不耐烦了。
Yeah. He said,
come back with the baby,
是的，他说把要么那婴儿带来。
or don't come back at all !
要么就不要回来！
I have a message for Soto.
给我带个信儿给索多。
Tell him , I'm bringing the baby.
告诉他，我会把那孩子带来。
And tell him , I'm bringing a mammoth.
再告诉他，我会带一只猛玛象来。
A mammoth.
一只猛玛象。
Mammoth never travels alone.
猛玛象从来不单独行动。
This one does.
And I'm leading him to half peak.
这只不同。
我会把他们带到山顶上。
Look at all that meat.
看看下面那些美味。
Let's get him !
Not yet!
我们去抓他！
不要。
We need the whole gang
to bring this mammoth down.
我们需要整个虎帮才能放倒那个猛玛象。
Get everyone ready.
叫每个人都准备好。
Now!
现在。
Where is the baby?
那孩子在哪？
You lost it?
你把它丢了？
Sid!
希德！
It's so ugly.
But it's adorable.
长的真错。
但蛮可爱的。
Hello, pumpkin.
你好，小南瓜。
Where did you find it?
你在哪找到他的？
The poor kid all alone in the wild.
这可怜的孩子一个人在野地里。
Sabers gang nailed on it.
So I just snatch it.
剑齿虎帮盯下他了，
所以我要带着他。
So brave.
真勇敢。
Well , he needed me and
I only wish I have with my home.
好的，他需要我，我也希望我和家人在一起。
Really?
真的？
I never attracted to a male.
对男人我可从来没什么吸引力。
Who wouldn't want a family, I always say.
我总是说：谁不想要个家。
Well , you know.
好的，你知道。
Cute kid, huh?
可爱的孩子？
So I was saying, ladies. . .
所以我说，女士们....
Hey! Mandy!
嗨！曼迪！
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了？
Excuse me, ladies.
报歉，女士们。
You just keep aggregating
and I'll be right back.
你们稍等片刻，我马上就回来。
He's not much to look at
but it's so hard to find a family guy.
他长的不怎么好看，但现在想找个能成家的男人
可不怎么容易。
Tell me about it.
But the sensitive ones get eaten.
给我说说。
但现在这些个头小的家伙容易被吃掉。
No, please.
I beg you, I need him .
不，我求你了。我需要他。
Why? A good looking guy like you?
为什么？像你这样的靓仔还需要他？
You say that but you don't mean it.
我知道你只是说说而已。
No, seriously, look at you.
不，我是认真的，看着我。
Most ladies, they don't stand the chance.
大多数的女士，她们可消受不了这种机会。
We have a very cool sense of humour.
我们都很有幽默感。
Don't let me crap this time.
这次可不要把我扯进来。
Thanks, man. You're the best.
谢谢。你是最棒的。
Without the baby.
Mandy, I need him .
别碰那孩子。
曼迪，我需要他。
So, ladies, where were we?
女士们，我们刚才讲到哪了？
Carlo?
Easy, Frankie.
卡罗？
放松，弗兰克。
Pretty tired, huh?
Somebody moves like a cheater.
累了吧？
有些人就像个骗子。
And that tiger.
比如说那只老虎。
Yeah, Mr. Great Tracker.
Can't even find a sloth.
是的，人类追踪先生。
连个树懒也找不到。
What am l? Head winder?
我是谁？猎人头？
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Look at you. You gonna
grow into a big predator, huh?
看看你自己。你能长成一只大型的食肉动物吗？
I don't think so.
我可不这么想。
What do you got?
You got. . .
看看你有什么？
你有....
Iittle patched fur,
no teeth, no claws.
一些碎毛发，
没有牙，没有抓子。
Your foot is skin-wrap in mulish.
What so threatening about you?
脚上被皮肤包着。
你拿什么来吓唬人？
Hey, am I like pillow a to you?
嗨，我是你的枕头吗？
Okay. All right, wise guy.
好的。不错，聪明的小孩。
You just started time out.
游戏才刚开始呢。
You think that's funny?
How about this?
你觉得这很好笑，是吗？
You'll lose snack in an hour.
一个小时下不来，你就没点心吃了。
I'm a little square to give you that.
我这么做，咱们就扯平点了。
Thank goodness.
谢谢上帝。
Oh, a tiger!
Help! Help!
噢，一只老虎！
救命！救命！
Where's the baby?
孩子在哪？
The rhinos are after me.
So think about it.
犀牛在追我。
你要救救我。
He got me!
Help. . .
他抓住我了！
救命....
Get away from me.
离我远点儿。
This way.
Over here.
这边。
在那。
No, Carlo!
The tiger beat us to him .
不，卡罗！
有只老虎帮我们杀了他。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
It's dead, all right.
他死了。好的。
No.
Carlo, where's your all upon?
不，卡罗，我们没事可做了。
I hate to bend like that.
But you know how it is.
我可不喜欢这么弯着腰。
你知道这是怎么回事。
All right, thanks.
You can put me down now.
好的，谢谢。
你可以放我下来了。
Mandy!
曼迪！
Guys, I thought we're in a hurry.
兄弟们，我想我们得快点儿。
When Diego speaks that out,
you're gonna wiped.
迭哥一说话，你就得救了。
Boy. For a second, I actually
thought you gonna eat me.
小子，当时我真觉得你要吃了我。
I don't eat junk food.
我从来不吃废物食品。
I thought you're gonna. . . Were you?
我觉得你是想....是不是？
Wait up. Wait up!
等一下，等一下！
Can you wait a second, please?
能等一下吗？
Hey, fellows!
嗨，兄弟们！
Thanks for waiting.
谢谢你们等我。
3, 2, 1 .
3，2，1 。
Sure is faithful .
真准时。
Don't make me reach back there.
He started it.
不要让我回头管这事。
是他先惹我的。
I don't care who started it.
I'll finish it.
我不管谁惹谁。
总之快停下。
Modern architecture.
It'd never last.
现代建筑。
它将永远留存。
Hey, Mandy.
Hey, Diego.
嗨，迭哥。
Hey, Sid.
嗨，希德。
You're lost, aren't you?
No, I know exactly where we are.
迷路了？
不，我知道我们在哪？
Ask him direction.
向他问问路。
I don't need direction.
Fine, I'll ask him .
我不用问路。
好的，我来问吧。
Hey, buddy. Have you seen
any human goes by here?
嗨，兄弟。看到那些人类往哪儿走了吗？
I love this thing.
我喜欢这事。
Okay, three words.
好的，三个词。
First word, stamp.
第一个词，“跺脚”。
Let me try.
让我一试试。
Pack.
Good word, Mandy.
“一群”。
猜的好，曼迪。
Long teeth?
长牙？
Great news
好消息。
I found a short cut
我找到一条捷径。
What do you mean short cut ?
你说的捷径是什么意思？
I mean it's faster that the
Long way around
我是说它比原先的路近的多。
I know what a short cut is
我知道捷径是什么了。
Either we slip through there and
Beat the past
我们要么走捷径找到他们，
Or take the long way and miss them
要么走原路错过他们。
What do you take me for?
你带我们走什么路？
This time you can be a free man
明天这个时候，你就自由了。
Hei guys check this out
嗨，兄弟们，看看这个。
The tiger found the short cut
虎仔找着了一条捷径。
No thanks I chose light
不用了，我还是走大路。
Did I suggest you take
The short cut ?
要我建议你走捷径吗？
Are you threatening me?
你在威胁我？
Move sloth
快走，树懒。
Stick together it's easy to get lost in
here
跟紧点儿，这里容易走散。
Fish
鱼。
I don't want to keep track
Of one baby
我可不想连孩子也丢了。
I got you
我抓你了。
Tell the kid to be more careful
告诉那孩子以后小心点儿。
Tigers
老虎。
It's ok
没事的。
Tigers are just playing with the
antilopes
老虎正和羚羊们玩呢。
With their teeth
用他们的牙齿。
Come on Sede
快来，希德。
Somebody pinched me
真烦人。
Look! This fat one
Just like you
看呀！这个胖家伙真像你。
Look he is playing with this kid
看呀，他正和那些孩子们玩呢。
See that's your problem
看到没，这就是你的问题。
That's what men're supposed to do
是男人都该这么做。
Find the shelters, have the babies . . .
找个居住地，生儿育女....
Sede
What ?
希德。
什么？
Shut up
闭嘴。
Look at this
看看这个。
Next stop.
Major pass
下一站。
大通道。
How could I ever doubted you ?
我以前真不应该怀疑你？
Did you hear that ?
你听到不？
You are almost home?
你快到家了。
I feel a sweat
我觉得有点出汗。
Do you have to get a new flask
Every time your body does something ?
你除得用新奶瓶吗？
你这个孩子次次都这么烦人。
Just ignore him
不用管他。
Seriously, my feet are really hot. . .
我是认真的，我的脚真的很热...
Tell me that was your stomach
告诉我那是你的胃在叫。
I am serious about this
我很认真。
From under . . ,
是从下面....
Come on keep up with me
出来的。
I wonder if you're moving
我在纳闷你在动吗？
I wish I'd jump like that
真希望我也能跳的这么远。
Come on move faster
快点，动作快点。
Mandy are you ok?
曼迪，你没事吧？
Come on say something Anything
来呀，说点什么，随便说点什么都行。
What I can't hear you
什么，我听不到你。
You are standing on my trunk
你站在我的鼻子上。
You're ok
你没事。
Why'd you do that ?
你为什么那么做？
You'd have died trying To save me
你会为了救我而送命的。
That' what you do when I'm hurt
要是你也会这么做的。
We guard for each other
我们互相保护。
Well . . .thanks
好的.....谢谢。
I don't now you guys
我真明白你们俩。
We're the weirdest herd I ever seen
我们是我见过最怪的一群。
I can't wait to get my
Claws on that mammal
我等不及要放倒那头猛玛象了。
No one touches until I get that baby
我没得到孩子之前，谁也不能碰他。
Knock it off I am starving
快停下，我饿死了。
I told you to knock it off
我告诉你，停下。
Save your energy
你省省吧。
Mammals don't go down easy
猛玛象可不这么容易对付。
There is only one way to do it
我们只有一个办法。
First you have to force him lnto a corner
首先，你要把它逼到角落里。
Cut off his ribs
咬断它的肋骨。
Then go for throat
然后是它的咽喉。
We gotta get this kid out Of the wind
我们得带这孩子去避避风。
How much further ? 3 miles
还有多远？3里。
what're you doing ?
你在干什么？
I'm painting sloth on a map
我在画树懒呢。
Why don't you make him look
Realistic and make him like down
你怎么不把它画的很现实的，很像的。
Make him rounder
画的更圆点儿。
I forgot how to laugh
我都快不会笑了。
I am a genius
我是个天才。
Now you have to refer me as
从现在开始，你们得叫我
Sid, Lord of the flame
“火神”希德。
Lord of the flame, your tail ls on fire
“火神”，你的尾巴着火了。
Thank you
谢谢你。
From now on I'm gonna call You Diego
从现在开始，我就叫你迭哥。
You touch me and you are dead
你敢碰我，你就死定了。
I am just kidding you little Nuthead
我只是开玩笑。
Look at this
看着。
I don't believe. . .
真不敢相信...
Come here
到这儿来。
Come to uncle Sid
到希德叔叔这里来。
No no this way
不，不到这边来。
No. go to him
不，去找他。
Ok
好的。
Good job
真不错。
Practise
继续练习。
A little guy growing up
一个孩子正在长大。
Come on sleep tight
来吧，该睡觉了。
You know I never had a friend
who'd Risk his life for me
你知道的，我从来没有一个朋友，
能为我舍弃生命。
Yeah he is a good guy
是的，他是个好人。
Yeah he is
是的。
Well , good night
好的，晚安。
What is your problem ?
你有什么问题？
Nothing it's freezing my Tail off
没什么。快走。冻的我的尾巴都要掉了。
Hey Diego you're frozen back there
嗨，迭哥，你在那冻住了吗？
Get down What
干啥趴下。
Get down and follow me
趴下跟着我。
What's going on?
怎么了？
There is an ambush waiting for you
前面有埋伏正等着你们。
What do you mean ambush
你说的“埋伏”是怎么回事？
You set us up ?
是你布的局？
It was my job, I was supposed to
Get the baby but. . .
这是我的工作。我本来就是来抓这个孩子的....
You pull us home for dinner
你把我们带到你家来当晚餐。
That's it you're out Of the herd
所以你才不会兽群在一起。
I am sorry
对不起。
No you are not . not yet
你有什么好对不起的？
Listen I can help you
听着，我能救你们。
Stay close Sid
靠近点，希德。
We can find our way out
我们能冲出去。
You can't . Pax is too strong
你们不行。派克斯太强大了。
You have to trust me
你们必须相信我。
Trust you ? why in the world
Would we trust you ?
相信你，为什么我们要相信你。
Cos I am your only chance
因为我是你们的唯一的机会。
Hello ladies
女士们，你们好。
Look who decided to show up
看看谁会露面。
Diego. I was beginning to
Worry about you
迭哥。我开始为你担心了。
No need to worry
不用担心。
In about 2 minutes you'll be
Satisfied your taste for revenge
不用两分钟，你就能尝到战利品的滋味了。
I see the sloth
我看到那个树懒了。
He got the baby
他带婴儿。
Don't give away your position
Until you see the mammal
看到猛玛象之前，不要离开作战位置。
He is the one you have to surprise
你们给他来个惊喜。
You wanna more, don't you think?
你不要多要点儿什么？
what are you waiting for?
你还在等什么？
no I said wait for the mammal
不，我说了要等那只猛玛象。
got you
抓你住你了。
eat my powder
吃我溅起来的雪吧。
sorry fellas you got a little surprise
不好意思，给了你们点儿惊喜。
ok follow me
好的，跟着我。
we take Sid up here where we can
我们把希德带上来吧。
come on Diego let's bring
this mammal down
来呀，希德。让我们放倒这只猛玛象。
that's right that's maybe. . .
这就对了，这可能是....
what are you doing ?
你在干什么？
Ieave the mammal alone
不要碰这只猛玛象。
I'll take you down first
我会首先放倒你。
We did it
我们成功了。
We were some team , huh?
我们还是朋友吗？
We're still a team
是的，我们还是朋友。
I am sorry I set you up
对不起，我骗了你们。
You know me I am too lazy To hold a bunch
你知道我太懒了，都不愿抱这个小孩了。
Knock it off
快停下。
You have to be strong
你得坚强起来。
You have to take care of mammal
你得照顾好曼菲德和希德。
Especially Sid
特别是希德。
You're a tiger I can carry you
你是只老虎，我能背着你。
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
Come on everything's gonna Be ok
没事的，一切都会好的。
Listen. You have to leave me here
听着。你们只能把我留在这儿。
Or the humans get to the pass
如果人们走过了那个通道。
You'll never catch them
你就永远也追不上他们了。
You didn't have to do that
你不必这样做。
That's what you do in The herd
为了大家，你必须得这么做。
Don't Forget about us , ok?
不要忘了我们，好吗？
We won't forget about you
我们不会忘记你的。
Good bye
再见。
That's right. Where is the baby ?
对了，那孩子在哪？
Come on Sid
不要这样，希德。
What is that sound?
什么声音？
Save your breath Sid
不要费劲了，你知道人们不能和我们交谈。
You're alive
迭哥，你还活着。
9 lives baby
一猫九命，我怎么会死。
you ok. I'll kiss ya
你没事，我要亲你。
welcome back partner want a lift ?
伙伴，欢迎回来。想坐个顺见车吗？
no thanks I gotta save whatever
dignity I got left
不，谢谢了。我还想留点儿尊严。
With us now, buddy.
Dignity has nothing To do with it
兄弟，我们在一起，跟“尊严”有什么关系。
But I'll take that lift
但我还是要搭这顺风车。
Climb upon
上来。
March!
快走！
Not march. , either way
或者不“快走”，随便你。
The End
剧终
Subtitles by: Reklame11
中文字幕独家制作:法兰克彼得生